linkedin.com/in/jefferycarmichael

(404) 729-1080

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Front & Back End Development | Application Programming Interfaces | Software Development Lifecycle

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Computer engineering technology graduate with a 2018 certificate in full stack web development; brings robust IT experience in programming, front-end website design, back-end databases, network engineering and telecom, technical troubleshooting and customer service and support. Experience ranges from building retail and non-profit websites, working on a 9/11 disaster recovery team to restore voice and data for AT&T after the 9/11 attacks, and reducing production error rates from 75% to 5% in an 18-month period, resulting in recognition from Lucent's CEO.

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Portfolio: https://jefferycarmichael.github.io/Portfolio/
Github: https://github.com/JefferyCarmichael

SKILLS & QUALIFICATIONS

BootstrapHTMLCSSJavaScriptjQueryAJAXReactJSXES6NodejsMongoDBMySQLFirebaseAngularMERN Stack

Git Version Control Adobe Photoshop

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CODE for AMERICA, Charlotte, NC

Community Fellow

 Developing a customizable application that provides formerly incarcerated people with a roadmap for accessing resources specific to their needs

MACY'S, Clearwater, FL

2008 - 2017

2019-Present

Customer Support Specialist

- Selected by IT manager for special project above responsibilities to install 1200 IP phones in the call center
- Consistently received numerous "outstanding" ratings in customer surveys when resolving customer issues

COMCAST, Alpharetta, GA

2007 - 2008

High Speed Internet Specialist

- Provided technical support for high speed internet and video service in a high volume call center environment
- Consistently achieved accuracy ratings over 95% for assessing technician deployment; saved company time and money on unnecessary technician calls
- Handled 60+ calls per day

PHOENIX STAIRS, Canton, GA

2005 - 2007

Estimator / Technical Support

- Efficiently and effectively researched and resolved technical problems for internal users
- Accurately evaluated project scope and developed estimates to create detailed work orders

JEFFERY CARMICHAEL Page 2

ADEX CORPORATION, Alpharetta, GA

Network Engineer

Provided detailed engineering of voice and data network projects for customers including AT&T and Bell South

- Selected for a cross-company team organized to improve delivery of engineering specifications
- Member of core transition team to migrate engineering services and systems from Lucent to Adex
- Managed vendor relationships to support service and system migration
- Developed and documented new engineering processes
- Actively sourced to join Adex network engineering team after a reduction in force at Lucent

LUCENT, Alpharetta, GA

2000 - 2003

2003 - 2005

Technical Staff / Design Engineer, Voice, ISDN, Broadband and Sonet Projects

- Switch engineer on the 9/11 disaster recovery team; restored voice / data for AT&T within 52 hours
- Led team of design engineers to develop medium to large voice and data network systems
- Completed engineering of six or more projects weekly valued between \$200,000 to over \$7 million per switch for customers such as AT&T, AT&T Wireless, Bell Atlantic, Media One, and Quest
- Managed time-sensitive engineering design projects to deliver sales revenue objectives; produced \$15 million in additional revenue
- Provided technical support to Bell Labs on the design of new systems configurations; Assembled and shipped two
 or more prototype models weekly during a four-year period
- Selected by IT Application Development Manager for a project above regular duties to develop mainframe software to deliver new products to customers; delivered application on schedule
- Managed quality team to resolve design errors created in manufacturing
- Reduced errors from 75% to 5% in 18 month period; received letter of recognition from CEO for leading the error resolution team

VOLUNTEER & COMMUNITY

Code for Charlotte, Charlotte, NC

2018 - present

Web Developer

- Assists in planning of new technology projects for the community

World Outreach Ministries, St. Petersburg, FL

2015 - 2018

Website Administrator

 Maintain global website utilizing HTML, CSS, WordPress and Adobe Photoshop; Managed website transition to WordPress; Recorded, edited and unloaded weekly podcasts

EDUCATION

B.S., Computer & Electrical Engineering Technology, Southern Polytechnic State University, Marietta GA **2018 Full Stack Web Development Certificate**, University of North Carolina at Charlotte